<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Highcharter on szumskiR</title>
    <link>/tags/highcharter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Highcharter on szumskiR</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>rszumski@gmail.com (Russell Szumski)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>rszumski@gmail.com (Russell Szumski)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/highcharter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Homicide Clearance Rate</title>
      <link>/post/chicago-homicide-clearance-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rszumski@gmail.com (Russell Szumski)</author>
      <guid>/post/chicago-homicide-clearance-rate/</guid>
      <description>If you’re murdered in America, there’s a 1 in 3 chance that the police won’t identify your killer.
To use the FBI’s terminology, the national “clearance rate” for homicide today is 64.1 percent. Fifty years ago, it was more than 90 percent.
Living in Chicago I often hear, from people outside of the city, how dangerous it is and how many murders go unsolved. So I thought I would take a look at the city’s “clearance” rate for myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Ran a Marathon Once</title>
      <link>/post/running-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rszumski@gmail.com (Russell Szumski)</author>
      <guid>/post/running-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>In 2016 I trained for and ran the Chicago Marathon. During the training I was wearing a Garmin Forerunner10 watch. I recorded all the stats the watch had, then did absolutely nothing with that data. It’s two years later, so I guess I should take a look at it.
When I trained I didn’t follow any training program. My idea was to run a lot, I think I did that, but at this point I have no Idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US Wildfires by County</title>
      <link>/post/us-wildfires-by-county/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rszumski@gmail.com (Russell Szumski)</author>
      <guid>/post/us-wildfires-by-county/</guid>
      <description>I watched Only the Brave, a 2017 American biographical action drama film that tells the true story of the Granite Mountain Hotshots, which lead me to the Kaggle 1.88 Million US Wildfires data set, then on to one of the Kernels titled Wildfire Exploratory Analysis which had some interesting analysis of wildfires in the US and a cool choropleth map of total US wildfires by County. That lead me to the highmaps section of highcharter, and finally I found my way to a ‘adding motion to choropleths’ blog post on jkunst that replicated a visualization made by New York Times showing How the Epidemic of Drug Overdose Deaths Rippled Across America.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Hertzsprung–Russell Diagram</title>
      <link>/post/hr-diagram/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rszumski@gmail.com (Russell Szumski)</author>
      <guid>/post/hr-diagram/</guid>
      <description>Fact, Hertzsprung–Russell diagrams (HR diagrams) are cool. They are one of the most important tools in the study of the way that stars change with time. Developed independently in the early 1900s by Ejnar Hertzsprung and Henry Norris Russell, it plots each star on a graph measuring the star’s brightness against its temperature (color). Depending on its initial mass, every star goes through specific evolutionary stages dictated by its internal structure and how it produces energy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>