<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ggplot2 on szumskiR</title>
    <link>/tags/ggplot2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ggplot2 on szumskiR</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>rszumski@gmail.com (Russell Szumski)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>rszumski@gmail.com (Russell Szumski)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ggplot2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sad Songs</title>
      <link>/post/gregory-alan-isakov/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rszumski@gmail.com (Russell Szumski)</author>
      <guid>/post/gregory-alan-isakov/</guid>
      <description>Tools: R
Data Source: Spotify
Gregory Alan Isakov has been one of my favorite singer-songwriters for a while, and I’ve gotten used to people suggesting that I play something ‘less depressing’. Most singer-songwriter’s music is indeed sad, but his music can’t be that sad. Can it?
Using the spotifyr package we can pull track audio features from the ‘Spotify’ Web API, including valence and energy of a track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather Is Not Climate</title>
      <link>/post/annual-temp-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rszumski@gmail.com (Russell Szumski)</author>
      <guid>/post/annual-temp-dev/</guid>
      <description>Tools: R
Data Source: NASA
I live in Chicago and it’s cold old, but weather is not climate. The difference between weather and climate is a measure of time. Weather is what conditions of the atmosphere are over a short period of time, and climate is how the atmosphere “behaves” over relatively long periods of time.
So lets take the data and plot the deviations from the 1951 - 1980 average going back to 1880 and see what it looks like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inaugural Addresses are more ... unintelligible</title>
      <link>/post/inaugural-address-smog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rszumski@gmail.com (Russell Szumski)</author>
      <guid>/post/inaugural-address-smog/</guid>
      <description>I come across an interesting infographic from the Guardian interactive team. It used the Flesch-Kincaid readability test to track the reading level of every State of the Union. I thought I’d give it a go and try to create something like it.
Instead of using the Flesch-Kincaid readability test I went with the Simple Measure of Gobbledygook (SMOG) grade, which is a measure of readability that estimates the years of education needed to understand a piece of writing, and I just looked at the Inaugural Addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump&#39;s sad iPhone Tweets</title>
      <link>/post/tweet-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rszumski@gmail.com (Russell Szumski)</author>
      <guid>/post/tweet-analysis/</guid>
      <description>White House director of social media Dan Scavino Jr. tweeted that Trump had switched his personal device to an iPhone. In the past Trump tweeted from his Andriod device and his staff from an iPhone. It was shown that the Android tweets where angrier and more negative.
Since the switch to an iPhone have the overall iPhone tweets become angrier and more negative?
The data It was reported that Trump got his new iPhone on March 25th, so first we’ll get the past 600 tweets from the realDonaldTrump using the twitteR package for R.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>